钱德，莫妮卡 香蕉核果松饼只剩一个
Chandler,Mon,there's only one banana-nut muffin left.
我先点的
I ordered mine first.
对，但我比你迅速
Yeah,but I'm so much faster.
给我
Give it to me.
不
No.
给我
Give it to me!
那给你吧
Okay,you can have it.
请慢慢享用你的咖啡
There you go. Enjoy your coffee.
我来之前它就在那了
That was there when I got here.
各位 你们绝对猜不到谁要来纽约
Hey,you'll never guess who's coming to New York.
菲比，在他吞下去以前说
Quick,tell us before he swallows.
我在海军服役的男朋友莱恩
Ryan,that guy I dated who's in the Navy.
你有个当海军的男友？
You went out with a guy in the Navy?
对，我在华盛顿广场 演奏吉他的时候认识的
I met him while playing guitar in the park.
莱恩丢咸水太妃糖给我 因为他没有零钱
Ryan threw in saltwater taffy because he didn't have change.
你的“咸水太妃男子”歌 就是那个时候写的？
Is that when you wrote "Saltwater Taffy Man"?
不，他是我的潜水艇男人 他两年出水一次…
No,he's my submarine guy. He resurfaces every couple years...
…然后我们有最不可思议的 三天相处的时间
...and we have an amazing three days together.
只是他这一次要来两个礼拜 整整两个礼拜 耶！
Only this time,he's coming for 2 weeks. Two whole weeks,which means "yea"!
等等，你是说这个家伙 每次一下水就是两年？
So this guy goes down for,like,two years at a time?
这是你舔我松饼的教训
That'll teach you to lick my muffin.
嗨
Hi.
怎么了？
Oh,no. What happened?
卡萝刚刚告诉我说 小班得了水痘
I just spoke to Carol. Ben's got chickenpox.
不
Oh,no.
所以如果你们还没有得过 那你们大概会得到
Yeah,so if you haven't had it,chances are you'll get it.
我得过了 我也得过了
-I've had it. -I've had it.
得过 得过
-Had it. -Had it.
我从来没得过 我觉得被遗忘了，看
I've never had it. I feel so left out. Oh,look!
六人行 第2季 第23集 出水痘
The One With the Chicken Pox
亲爱的，你又铺床了
Honey,you made the bed again.
我说过，你不用铺床的 又不是夏令营
I told you,you don't have to do that. This isn't camp.
那我猜昨晚我被女式运动裤袭击 完全没有道理了
Then I guess the panty raid last night was totally uncalled for.
我要去洗澡了今天我要唱杰姆克劳奇的“勒罗伊布朗”
I'm taking a shower. Today I'll sing Jim Croce's "Leroy Brown."
莫妮卡，我有个问题
Hey,Mon,I have a question.
勒罗伊是 “全镇最坏的男人”…
Is Leroy the baddest man in the whole damn town...
…还是“全镇最胖的男人”
...or the fattest man?
最坏，不然那首歌就会叫 “胖胖的勒罗伊布朗”
The baddest. Otherwise,the song would be "Fat,Fat Leroy Brown."
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
只是在等你，甜心
I'm just waiting for you,sweetie.
你在重新铺床吗？
Are you remaking the bed?
对不起… 你铺的样子完全没有问题
I'm sorry. The way you did it,it was just fine.
那你重新铺是因为…？
Then you're redoing it because...?
说出来你会认为我疯了
You'll think I'm crazy.
你说不说都会有这个危险
You're pretty much running that risk either way.
你看…
Okay. You see...
…被子的商标 不该在床的左上角
...the duvet tag shouldn't be at the top left corner...
…应该在床的右下角才对
...it should be at the bottom right corner.
那不会很疯狂 这只是开头，先让你轻松一些
-That's not so crazy. -I'm just easing you in.
好
All right.
你看到这些小花了吗？
You see these little flower blossoms?
那应该往上不是往下…
They should be facing up not down...
…因为床头的位置 是太阳的方向
...because the head of the bed is where the sun would be.
你不再爱我了，是不是？
You don't love me anymore,do you?
事实上，如果可能的话 我会更爱你了
Actually,if it's possible,I love you more.
真的？
Really?
那来吧…
Wow. Well,then,come on!
我要教你 怎么把卫生纸折出尖角来
I wanna show you how to fold the toilet paper into a point.
如果你需要一个工作应急的话…
If you need something to hold you over...
…我可以给你一个 基层的资料处理员的工作
...I can get you a job here as an entry-level processor.
那种工作难道不需要经验吗？
Don't you need experience?
要学也不困难
It's not hard to learn.
如果你怕别人看出 你不晓得自己在干什么的话 你是演员啊
As for people realizing you don't know what you're doing,you're an actor.
那就扮演一个处理员 人们就会相信你是个处理员了
Act like a processor,people will think you're a processor.
钱德，这是今早的预算表
Here's this morning's projections.
谢了，史考 这是乔伊
Thanks. Scott Alexander,Joey Tribbiani.
乔伊他也是一个处理员
Joey is a fellow processor.
真的？
No kidding?
我处理 人要找人处理，他们会找我
I process. People want the processing,I'm the one they call.
你在哪儿工作？ 我正在转业当中
-Where do you work? -Well,I'm in between things.
你也知道的嘛 今天你还在处理，到了明天…
You know,one day you're processing,the next day...
…你就没有那么多可以处理的了
...you're not so much processing anymore.
我正要告诉乔伊 弗雷茨曼的部门刚组建
I told Joey about the opening in Fleischman's group.
弗雷茨曼的部门
Fleischman's group.
那你要记住别碰他的三明治啊
Whatever you do,don't touch his sandwiches.
你的处理员都是傻蛋，是不是？
Are all you processors dorks?
你擦上这口红真美
This lipstick looks just great on you.
你美呆了，真的
You look fabulous. You really do.
你们确定吗？ 真的吗？
Yeah,are you sure? Really?
瞧，美得不得了 看在上帝的份上，把灯调暗
See,you look beautiful. For God sakes,dim the lights.
我好恐怖喔
I'm hideous!
不会有问题的
It's gonna be okay.
莱恩一直在水下
Ryan's been underwater.
你屁股没有长藤壶 他就该谢天谢地了
He's just gonna be glad you don't have barnacles on your butt.
请进
Come in.
宝贝，我回来了…
Hey,baby,I'm back
莱恩，你好吗？
Hey,Ryan. What's up?
你怎么了？
What's going on?
不要… 不要再往前走了
No,no. You have to stay back.
我长痘痘了
I have the pox!
水痘还是天花（性病）？
Chicken or small?
水痘（又名鸡痘），很讽刺 因为我根本就不吃鸡
Chicken,which is so ironic considering I'm a vegetarian.
那为什么不在家里休息？ 因为我外婆没得过水痘
-Why aren't you home in bed? -My grandmother's never had chickenpox.
拜托，告诉我你得过 老天，我忘了你多可爱了
Please tell me you have,because oh,my God,I forgot how cute you are.
抱歉，我没得过
I'm sorry,I never had them.
如果可以许一个愿的话 要回到我七岁…
If I had one wish,I'd go back to when I was 7...
…吉米得水痘的时候 我会抓住他的手在我脸上蹭
...when Jimmy Hauser had chickenpox,and rub that kid all over my face.
对呀，或许你也可以希望 我现在没有得水痘
Yeah,or you could wish that I didn't have them now.
我可以看你的脸吗？
Can I see your face?
不行 你不会想看一张痘子脸的
No. You don't wanna see a face covered with pox.
就算长满熏鲑鱼我也不会在乎
It could be lox,I wouldn't care.
可是你恨鱼
And you hate fish.
真贴心，好吧
So sweet. All right.
那你看嘛
Okay,all right. You can see.
这就是我
This is me.
很抱歉
Sorry!
我很吓人吗？
I am scary!
不，是闪电 刚才的闪电真是很不巧
The lightening was an unfortunate coincidence.
你很漂亮，你真的很漂亮
You look lovely! Lovely!
好讨厌
I hate this.
告诉你，我计划了 两个最不可思议的礼拜
I had the most amazing two weeks planned for us.
而我所计划的一切 都得比现在更为亲密
And everything I had in mind,we had to be a lot closer than this.
我跟一群男人 在钢管里关了八个月…
I've spent the last eight months in a steel tube with men...
…我一直祈盼的就是这个时刻
...thinking about this moment.
我不会让这里…
I am not gonna let a bunch...
…也痒，那里也痒 分开我们两个
...of itchy spots stand between us.
这是我得过的最浪漫的病
Okay. This is the most romantic disease I've ever had.
第一天上班怎么样？ 蛮好的，就像你说的
-How's the first day? -Good. It's like you said.
大部分只是把数字 从一栏放到另一栏而已
It's putting numbers from one column into another.
我跟你说过了
There you go.
而且大家都很好，我刚才跟那个红发女士聊天，叫金妮的
And everybody's nice. I just had a good talk with that lady Jeannie.
金妮？东岸营业部的总裁金妮
Jeannie? The head of East Coast operations,Jeannie?
原来我们的孩子上同一所学校
Turns out our kids go to the same school.
世界真小
Yeah. Small world,huh?
世界真怪
Weird world.
你的孩子？
Your kids?
我猜我的角色有孩子
I figure my character has kids.
那句话我没有一个字听得懂的
There isn't a part of that sentence I don't need explained.
你瞧，演戏的时候 你需要思考那类的事情
When you're acting,you need to think about that stuff.
我的角色，资料处理员乔瑟夫夫…
My character,Joseph the processing guy...
…有两个女儿，艾士莉跟布妮
... has two little girls,Ashley and Brittany.
布妮做什么艾士莉都要学
Ashley copies everything Brittany does.
有时隐形小孩就是那个样子的
Well,invisible kids can be that way sometimes.
乔瑟夫夫跟他太太凯伦 正考虑再生一个
You know,Joseph and his wife,Karen,are thinking of having a third kid.
知道吗？
You know what?
刚刚生了
Just did.
我想你那想像的精子 一定非常强
That's some pretty powerful imaginary sperm you must have there.
你知道什么比痒更难受吗？
IKnow what makes the itching worse?
你要继续提这个吗？
That you don't stop talking about it?
好 只要专心的玩嘛
-Fine. -Let's just play,okay?
好
Good,okay.
要丢了，十二
Here we go,double sixes.
要丢了…
Here we go....
来妈妈这里，准备要滚色子
Come to Mama. Getting ready to roll the dice....
你在干什么？你在抓痒？
What are you doing? Are you scratching?
没有，我在祈求好运
No. This is what I do for luck,okay?
你在抓痒
You're scratching.
把色子给我
Give me the dice.
把色子给我 不要，好嘛…
-Give me the dice. -No! Here. There!
看，十二
Look,double sixes!
我们不能抓，会留下疤
We can't scratch. We'll scar.
可是我没有办法不去想那个，太难了啦
I can't stop thinking about it. It's just so hard.
我只想抓住这些房子 磨擦我的全身
I wanna grab these houses and rub them all over my body.
不可以 给我
-No! -Give it!
来呀，给我
Come on!
你知道你要的 你知道你也要，对不对？
You know you want it. You know you want it too.
就坏一次吧，感觉会很棒的
Let's just be bad. It'll feel so good.
来吧…
Come on.
上帝帮帮我吧
Oh,God,help me.
好棒 好，现在换我了
-Oh,yeah. -Okay,good. Now do me.
来，抓我的背 来吧，快点，用力…
Do my back. Oh,come on. Harder!
我来了
There you go.
别动 为什么？
-Don't move. -Why?
不要动 干嘛…？
-Don't move. -What are you...?
住手，马上住手
Stop that. Stop that right now.
我相信你会这样，菲比 但是莱恩，你是个军人呀
I might've expected this of Phoebe. But,Ryan,you're a military man.
她逼我这么做的
She made me do it.
你脸上的颜色真不错
That's a nice color on you.
是的，变成粉红色的疤了，宝贝
Yeah, well, it comes in pink and blotchy, baby.
我希望你的“香肠”也长痘痘
I hope you get a weenie pock.
你跟米顿得来坐我们的船 带孩子们来
You and Milton have to join us on the boat. Bring the kids.
咱们好好玩一天
We'll make a day of it.
听起来好棒 我们得好好安排一下
That sounds lovely. We'll have to set it up.
我最好回去了 希望你的宝宝好点了
I better get back. Hope the baby feels better.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢了，拜拜，金妮 拜拜，乔瑟夫
-Bye-bye,Jeannie. -Bye-bye,Joseph.
好虚伪
What a phony.
她在码头一脚踩了个空的时候她就会学到你的教训了
You'll teach her a lesson when she steps off the dock onto nothing.
嗨，道格拉斯先生
-Hey,Mr. Douglas. -Sir.
听着，备忘录我收到了 我们下周五才能看到系统报告吗？
Bing,I got your memo. We're not gonna see the report until next Friday?
我组里的人希望这个周末 能够跟家人一起共度
My group wants to spend the holiday with family.
我也有家庭 但我还是会来这儿
I have a family. I'm gonna be here.
是啊，宾，你干嘛呢？
Yeah,Bing. What's that about?
我要让我的人稍微喘一口气 以提高士气
It's about cutting them a little slack for morale.
如果你想看大概数字 我可以在星期三以前给你
Look,I can get some rough numbers by Wednesday.
大概数字？
Rough numbers?
公司不是建在大概数字上 我说得对吗，道格拉斯先生？
This company wasn't built on rough numbers. Right,Mr. Douglas?
星期二以前 把正确数字放在我桌上
Have the final numbers on my desk by Tuesday.
照你的意思做吧
If you say so,sir.
乔瑟夫很行，是不是？
Joseph's good,isn't he?
乔伊，我要杀了你
I'm going to kill you.
嘿，我把乔瑟夫定位成那种喜欢搅合的人
Hey,I just figured Joseph's the kind of guy who likes to mix it up.
你知道，一头钻入，激怒某人
You know,get in there,ruffle some feathers.
为什么？
Why?
听着，抱歉，但乔瑟夫就是那样
Look,I'm sorry,but that's what Joseph does.
你想耍花招的话…
Okay? If you try to pull something...
…他会揭发你
... he'll call you on it.
他会说“你耍什么花招？”
"What are you trying to pull?" he'll say.
胶带
Duct tape.
我是不是也该带点什么来？
Was I supposed to bring something too?
这是给那对痒双胞胎的 我把手套粘在他们手上
This is for the scratchy twins. I taped oven mitts to their hands.
你真严
You're strict.
这是为他们好啊
Well,it's for their own good.
莫妮卡，我很欣赏你有效率的把胶带的一端折起来
You know,I like the way you have efficiently folded this tab under.
你看，急需用胶带的时候 可省下好几秒宝贵的时间
See,in a tape emergency you could shave valuable seconds off your time.
正是
Exactly!
真高兴在你面前 可以完全的神经质
God,I love that I can be totally neurotic around you now.
告诉我实话
Tell me the truth.
难道你不喜欢现在你桌上的一切都是直角吗？
Don't you like having everything on your desk perpendicular?
如果它们不是直角 那就是错角
If it's not a right angle,it is a wrong angle.
很好 谢谢
-Very good. -Thank you.
你知道吗？ 明天我要改你的时钟
Tomorrow,I'm gonna do your clocks.
你要怎样改我的时钟？
You're gonna do what to my clocks?
我要把它调成我的时间
Set them to my time.
这我搞糊涂了
I'm confused.
时间不是都一样的吗？
I thought we shared time.
不…瞧 我把房间的时钟调快了六分钟
No. See,in my bedroom I set my clock six minutes fast.
想不想知道原因？
Wanna know why?
因为这里跟厨房在不同的时区里？
Because it's in a slightly different time zone than the kitchen?
算了，我不想要说了
Forget it.
来嘛，告诉我嘛
No,come on,tell me.
不，因为你不会明白 来嘛
-You don't understand. -Come on.
不，你根本没有 任何可爱的小怪癖
You don't have any obsessive things.
那不对…
No,that's not true.
是吗？ 好吧，说一个来听听
Oh,yeah? Tell me one of yours.
譬如说吧，我总是 把我的运动袜…
One of my things is I always separate my sweat socks...
…跟西装袜分开来摆
...from my dress socks.
如果搞混了会怎样？
What if they get mixed up?
天啊，那我会…
Boy,I would just....
我会发狂
I would freak out.
你才不会
You would not.
我真不敢相信 真讨厌你那么正常
I can't believe this. I hate this. You're too normal.
真不敢相信我的男友没怪癖
I can't believe you don't have a "thing."
我的男友没有怪癖（与“东西”同词）
My boyfriend doesn't have a "thing."
如果有人听到你这句话 别人会怀疑我无能
See,if anyone overheard that,I didn't come off well.
道格拉斯先生正在找你 为什么要找我？
-Mr. Douglas is looking for you. -Why is Mr. Douglas looking for me?
因为他怀疑 你搞砸那个出借规划
He suspects you dropped the ball on the Lender project.
他…为什么要怀疑我？
Why? Why does he suspect that?
因为原先他以为是乔瑟夫…
At first,he thought it was Joseph...
…但在问了乔瑟夫之后 发现结果是你
...but after he asked Joseph about it,turns out it was you.
反正我想你应该知道啦 好吧，够了
-Anyway,I thought you should know. -All right. That's it.
听我说，乔伊…
Look,Joey...
…对不起，我了解这是你 这辈子最重要的一个角色…
... I realize this is the role of a lifetime for you...
…若我可以只开除乔瑟夫就好了 不幸的是，那是不可能的
...and if I could just fire Joseph,I would. But that's not possible.
所以我必须要开除你们两个
So I have to let you both go.
你在胡扯什么？大家都爱乔瑟夫
What? Everybody loves Joseph.
我不爱，我恨乔瑟夫
I don't. I hate Joseph.
我认为他是个褐色鼻子的马屁精
I think he's a brown-nosing suck-up.
是吗？你不能开除他 因为他不在你的部门
You can't fire Joseph. He's not in your department.
好吧…我不能开除他…
All right,okay. So I can't fire Joseph...
…但是我可以跟他老婆睡
... but I can sleep with his wife.
凯伦，不！
Not Karen!
我正在考虑跟她搞婚外情
Yeah,I'm thinking about having an affair with her.
你知道吗？
You know what?
刚搞了
I just did.
你对我做了什么，老兄？
What the hell are you doing?
不是我
Oh,it's not me.
是我的角色
It's my character!
钱迪
Chandie.
对，为了好玩 而引诱同事老婆的坏处理员…
The rogue processor who seduces his coworkers' wives...
…隔天在饮水机旁边当笑话讲
...and then laughs about it.
其实她的内裤就在我的抽屉里
In fact,I have her panties right there in my drawer!
真的吗？ 假的，疯子，根本没有这个人
-Really? -No,freak show,she's fictional!
放轻松一点
Take it easy.
这对你那么重要的话 那我找别的事做好了
If it means that much to you,I'll go find something else.
谢谢你
Thank you.
只是我会想念乔瑟夫的
It's just that I'm gonna miss Joseph.
我喜欢他，和他太太
I liked him. His wife.
她好火辣
She was hot.
还有孩子们 知道吗，他原本打算明年夏天建个池塘的
And the kids. You know he was gonna put in a pool next summer.
拜托你拆掉，我发誓我不抓了
Please take these off. I swear I won't scratch.
对不起，莫妮卡的命令
No,sorry,hon. Monica's orders.
上厕所真不容易
Well,that wasn't easy.
晚餐好了
Okay,dinner's on.
烤箱里还有一个桃子饼在保温
There's a peach cobbler warming in the oven.
盘子会很烫手 但对你们来说应该不成问题
So the plate's gonna be hot,but that shouldn't be a problem for you.
好了，孩子们，拜拜
All right,you kids. Bye,now.
拜拜 你们看
-Bye. -Oh,look,look.
低成本的木偶剧
A low-budget puppet show.
真可惜你看不到 我举起的是哪一根手指
A shame you can't see what finger I'm holding up.
酒？ 麻烦你
-Wine? -Please.
洒出来了 我来
-Spilled some. -I got it.
我得告诉你，你今晚好美
You look beautiful tonight.
你说什么？
What?
对不起
Sorry.
你好美
You look beautiful.
够了，我受够了
You know what? That's it. That's it.
真好
Oh,yes.
好
Good.
你们…
You guys,did you?
莫妮卡…
Monica...
…醒醒
...wake up.
什么事？
What's up?
我想到一个了
I thought of a thing.
是吗？
Yeah?
对，我必须睡…我必须… 睡床的这一边
I have to sleep,have to,on this side of the bed.
你不得不睡床的这一边…
No. You have to sleep on this side of the bed...
…是因为我必须睡床的这一边
... because I have to sleep on this side of the bed.
或者是因为我让你那么认为
Or so I would have you believe.
没什么大不了啊 每个人都有一半儿的床
So you have a side of the bed. Everybody has a side of the bed.
别这样嘛 你还没听我的理由呢
Hey,come on. You haven't heard my reason yet.
好啊，说吧
All right,go on.
我必须睡在床的西边…
I have to sleep on the west side...
因为我是在加利福尼亚（美国西部）长大的
... because I grew up in California...
…睡东边的话…
...and otherwise...
…海洋的方向就错了
...the ocean would be on the wrong side.
天啊
Oh,my God.
你真变态
You're a freak!
你觉得怎么样？
How about that?
莱恩，你这次要潜到哪里？
Where're you shipping off to?
我真的不能说
I really can't say.
那你们潜水艇上有核武器吗？
Do you have nuclear weapons onboard?
我不能说
I can't say.
那你是不是可以用潜水望眼镜看东西？
Do you get to look through a periscope thingy?
对不起，我不能说
I'm sorry,but I can't say.
学潜水艇的知识真酷
Wow,it's neat learning about submarines.
该走了不然会错过飞机 我送你出去
-I better not miss my flight. -I'll walk you out.
再见，莱恩 保重
-Bye,Ryan. -Pleasure. Take care.
你想我们可以 弄套制服给你穿吗？
So do you think we could get you one of those uniform things?
你喜欢，是不是？
You like that,do you?
是呀
Oh,yeah.
我去打电话订
I'll make some calls.
你相信我们两个礼拜 是这样共度的吗？
Can you believe that's how we spent our two weeks?
我知道，我计划的浪漫事都没有做…
We didn't do the romantic things I'd planned...
…像去中央公园野餐 还有来中央公园喝咖啡
...Iike having a picnic in Central Park and coffee at Central Perk.
我们刚喝过了
Oh,I just got that!
计程车
Taxi!
再见
Bye,you.
对不起，我们已经…
I'm sorry,we're
水手
Hey,sailor.
这是你心里想的吗？
Is this what you had in mind?
可不是嘛
I'll say.
我明天就要出海了
I'm shipping out tomorrow.
那么…
Well,then...
…我们最好算上今晚
...we better make this night count.
等等，我忘了关卡布奇诺咖啡机了
Wait,I forgot to turn off the cappuccino machine.
起锚吧
Anchors aweigh.
等等… 我的皮包
Oh,wait,wait! My purse,my purse!
我忘了关洗手间的灯
I forgot to turn off the bathroom light.
我们干脆楼上见好了
Why don't I just meet you upstairs?
亲爱的
Honey!